( Sizzling )
( Woman ) Stop that !
( Boy ) Stop what ? I 'm not doing anything .
( Slap )
( Boy ) Ow ! ( Woman ) Serves you right .
( Woman ) Will you cut that out ? ( Boy ) I can 't help myself .
You 're as sneaky as your father was .
He was the tomato thief of all time .
- I know what you 're doing . - I 'm hungry .
Let me finish dinner before you eat it . Chop these .
Sorry , fellas .
Oh , Mom , tomorrow night we 're going with Tiffany to buy a Christmas tree .
OK , but a small one . Watch your fingers .
No way , a big one . Ow ! Shit !
- Are you OK ? - Yeah , it adds flavour .
( Phone )
- Hello ? - We don 't want any .
Thea who ?
I know it 's Thea Brody . How many grandkids do I have ?
- ( Girl ) ' I can call by myself . ' - I know . You 're a big girl .
- ' I 'm five now , Grandma . ' - I know you 're five .
Hi , kiddo . How 're you doin ' down there ?
'I 'm fine , Uncle Sean . I 'm taking swimming lessons . '
- ( Man ) ' She swims like a fish . ' - Michael !
- Hey , bro . - The fish . Check it .
- No way ! You check it . - I 'm on the phone .
- ( Thea ) ' What 's going on ? ' - Your grandmother is a slave driver !
- Did you get the book ? - ( Man ) ' Yeah . Thanks ! '
Ask the big doctor about his job . Tough life , you Bahamian beach bum .
'I heard that . '
- He heard that . - Good .
Hey , how come you get to leave early ?
Cos my desk is closer to the door .
- ( Sean ) A big one . - No , your brother won 't be here .
- Merry Christmas ! - Merry Christmas , Jim .
- Eggnog time Thursday night ! - We 'll be there .
We are getting a big tree for all the old ornaments ...
- With stockings on the mantle ... - And cookies and beer for Santa .
All right ! Tiffany , do you realise what a madman you 're marrying ?
Yes , I do .
- I gotta check in . - OK .
- See you . Love you . - Bye . Me , too .
- ( Ellen ) Don 't be late ! - Yeah , yeah , yeah , yeah .
( Slams shut )
That bad , huh ?
We 're out of decaf , petty cash and requisition forms .
Anything to do before I go ?
That man keeps calling about his training film .
He won 't believe we don 't have a SWAT team .
( Phone )
Good night , Polly !
Amity Police Department .
( Door closes )
Hold it !
There 's an old dock piling in the channel .
Maybe it 'll just keep on drifting till it goes away ?
- It 's stuck on a channel marker . - Good night , Polly .
( Door closes )
Uh-huh . It ... Hold it !
It has to be cleared before the fishermen come back .
Where 's Lenny ?
Out to Ben Master 's place . Cow tipping .
Cow tipping ?
Says kids tip over his sleeping cows . They 're not givin ' milk .
OK , I 'll take care of it .
Deputy Brody will take care of it personally .
Call home , tell ' em I 'll be late .
- Uh-huh . - Cow tipping !
# The first Noel
# The angels did say
# Was to certain poor shepherds
# In fields as they lay ... #
- No , no , no , no ! Hold it ! - # In fields ... #
Hold it ! Together , people ! Together , remember ?
All right . Let 's try it again . Two , three .
# ( Band intro ) #
Where the hell are the Wise Men ?
Good luck , Harry .
I 'm gonna need it with this bunch .
Sounds better than when I was a shepherd .
( Harry ) Joseph , where the hell is your robe ?
You 're supposed to be in costume ! Jesus !
I 'm over here !
# In fields as they lay
# In fields where they
# Lay keeping their sheep
# On a cold winter 's night
# That was so deep
# Noel , Noel , Noel , Noel
# Born is the King of Israel #
( Harry ) All right , clear quickly . Ready , angels , and ...
# Hark , the herald angels sing
# Glory to the newborn King
# Peace on Earth and mercy mild
# God and sinners reconciled
# Joyful all ye nations rise
# Join the triumph of the skies
# With angelic hosts proclaim
# Christ is born in Bethlehem
# Hark , the herald angels sing
# Glory to the newborn King #
( Harry ) Very good , people . Very good . And now , again , ' Noel , ' everyone .
# The first Noel ... #
( Screaming )
( Panting and groaning )
Oh , God !
# On a cold winter 's night ... #
Oh , God ! Help !
# That was so deep
( Screams )
Help me !
Oh , God ! Help me !
# Born is the King ... #
# Israel #
( Singing in distance )
( Shrieks in terror )
His things . I thought you 'd want them .
( Sobbing )
Grandma ! Grandma !
( Humming )
( Dog barking )
( Thea ) We 're here !
Grandma ?
- Mom ? - We 're here .
Thea , get down here . Come on .
Anybody home ?
Michael .
Where 's Mom ?
She 's been out there for hours .
How 's she doing ?
We 've just come from Tiffany 's house .
Poor girl . The doctors had to sedate her .
- Hello , Mrs Taft . - Hi , sweetheart .
I didn 't recognise you , Thea . You 're so grown up .
Uncle Sean is dead , you know .
- Will he ever come back ? - We 'll talk about that more later .
( Mrs Taft ) Are you hungry ?
( Thea ) I had a hamburger on the plane .
( Polly ) We can do better than that . How about a funny bone sandwich ?
( All laughing )
( Polly ) How was the aeroplane ride ? ( Thea ) Good . I got two lollipops .
( Seagulls call )
- It came for him . - What ?
It waited all this time , and it came for him .
You guys must be starving . I 'll make some fettuccini .
I 'm making dinner . You should sit and relax .
Really , Ellen , there 's nothing left to do .
( Clattering )
I want you to get out of the water .
What ?
I want you to give up that terrible job !
- You can 't be serious . - Damn right .
I 'm just getting started .
- I don 't want you near the water . - Mom , you 're upset .
I don 't want my family anywhere near the water again .
- Never ! - You can 't believe that voodoo .
Sharks don 't pick people to murder .
It picked out Sean . It killed your father .
- Dad died from a heart attack . - He died from fear .
Mom , Mom , Mom , Mom , listen to me .
There 's never been a great white where we live , ever .
It 's warm water . They don 't like it .
Your brother 's dead . Your father 's dead .
( Door closes )
It was a piece of wood ! It was a shitty piece of wood !
Michael !
He was just doing his job .
God , he could make me laugh sometimes .
He was always tagging ' after me when we were kids .
He always wanted to do what I was ...
Hey , where are you going ?
Nowhere !
( Man ) ' To everything there is a season ,
'and a time to every purpose under heaven .
'A time to be born and a time to die .
'A time to plant ,
'and a time to pluck up that which is planted .
'A time to kill and a time to heal .
" A time to break down and a time to build up .
" A time to weep and a time to laugh . '
'A time to mourn and a time to dance .
'A time to cast away stones
'and a time to gather stones together .
'A time to embrace
'and a time to refrain from embracing . '
( Boy ) Hey , Tom , wait up !
Oh , you 're gonna spoil her .
That 's what grandmas are for .
( Laughing )
Why don 't you come down to the islands with us ?
- I ... I can 't do that . - Come on , Mom .
- Get warm , spend time with Thea ... - Yes !
( Laughing ) Come here , you .
Wanna know what I think ? I think it 's a wonderful idea .
- Yes . - Come on , at least consider it .
- Get away . You shouldn 't be alone . - Yes !
- Great ! - Yay !
- We can catch the 4.30 ferry . - ( Ellen ) Today ?
- Today . - No , I can 't .
( Thea ) Yes , you can .
( Ferry horn )
- Swing me , swing me ! - OK , OK .
Oh , my back ! I can 't do this .
I 'll take her . Oh , my God , she 's too heavy .
Help us , Daddy .
OK , here we go . Aeroplane ride .
( Thea laughs )
I know . I 'm gonna throw you overboard .
( Laughing continues )
( Violent sobbing )
( Ferry horn )
Oh , look !
( Carla ) Oh , hey , I always wanted to ride one of those .
( Michael ) No way . ( Carla ) Chicken .
Mom always said if God meant us to ride parachutes for fun ,
- we 'd be born with tickets . - I never said that .
Yes , you did . August 1977 .
Where 's the lady who brings the soda ?
They had them on the big plane .
There 's some coffee in the Thermos .
I 'm too young for coffee . Can I drive ?
( Carla ) Thea !
Sometimes Dad puts me in his lap and lets me steer the Jeep .
Sometimes I let interesting people sit in my lap and steer the plane .
- Oh , really ? - Really .
- Hoagie ? - Yeah ?
Jake says you 'll have to fly the rest of your life
to pay off what you lost at craps .
Good news travels fast . I 'll get it back next time .
How come it bumps up and down when there 's no road ?
The wind does that .
You been to the Bahamas before ?
- No . - First time 's the best .
Then you know too much and nothing 's the same .
What makes the plane go up and down ?
Easy . You go like this , and the houses get bigger .
( Laughing and gasping )
Then you go like this , and the houses get smaller .
( All shout )
- Do you wanna go for a ride ? - ( All ) Yes !
( All screaming , laughing )
( Man ) # And so I 'm offering this simple phrase
# To kids from one to 92
# Although it 's been said
# Many times , many ways
# Merry Christmas
# To you #
Kenny and Tamika are playing on the dock . Hurry , hurry , hurry !
( Children shouting )
( Michael ) Everybody out !
- Come on . - Kenny , Tamika ! I 'm back ! I 'm home !
Let me help you with the bags there , Romeo .
- You can take the heavy ones . - Thanks , buddy .
Grandma ! Grandma !
Your room 's in here .
Grandma , watch me ! Grandma !
Thea ! Get down from there !
- Grandma , watch me ! - Get down from there !
- Mommy lets me . - It 's too dangerous ! Don 't do that !
- Grandma , watch me ! - Come on , sweetheart .
But you always let me .
Not today . Come on , Thea .
The other kids are .
Daddy , why can 't I ?
Did you hear what I said ? Come inside the house right now !
- I don 't want to . I wanna swing . - Right now you have to unpack .
I didn 't mean to start all this . I feel like such a grandma .
Come on . I 'll show you around .
No ! No ! Put me down !
- Will you stop making a scene ? - I wanna swing !
I 'll be all right , Michael .
Good . So will I.
( Michael ) She calls it 'Tourist on the Loose ' .
The local government commissioned it for the public beach .
- ( Carla ) You forgot about the store . - Oh , yeah . Yeah .
( Carla ) We need milk , bread ...
There 's a big unveiling ceremony .
- ( Carla ) We need beer ! - OK , I 'll be right there !
Pretty good , huh ?
Yeah .
( Gasping )
( Screaming )
( Gasps )
Grandma ?
( Panting )
( Man on radio ) 'Will you stop farting ' around ?
'Michael , what the hell you doin ' down there , eh ? '
Jake , stop busting ' my chops .
'Listen , you remember what they look like ?
'Hard on the outside , chewy on the inside .
'Sometimes they come with a little grime .
'Move your ass , man ! '
( Michael ) Ah , bingo !
( Jake ) Good . How many you got ?
Come on , Michael , talk to me . Give me some numbers . How many ?
- ' Leave me alone . ' - You 're full of shit .
'You been down there all day , nothin ' to show but excuses .
'Michael , you 're tagging ' the damn things . '
I gotta separate the ladies from the gentlemen first .
No , man , don 't . You move too slow . You got two speeds - slow and slower .
Hold your water , Jake . The females have eggs .
So we 're gonna stop everything and pass out cigars ?
We 're being paid to see where they go , how they propagate .
If we had decent funding , I 'd study their motor systems , temperature ...
We 'd do a decent report for a change and really give them something .
If you 'd leave me alone , I 'd be able to do my work .
I know how to tag a damn conch .
- Your readings suck , man . - The tags suck .
- No , it 's I that made them . - It 's I that put ' em on .
- You put ' em on wrong . - No , no , no ! They leak !
A blind man could find more conch !
You can 't find your ass with both hands !
That 's not fair ! You go away , come back a zombie , it 's Christmas Eve .
- We 're working overtime cos of YOU ! - Hey !
I 'm sorry about your brother , man .
Well , just ... just take it easy , will ya ?
Jake .
C 'mon , Jake , don 't ... I don 't want ...
- Oh ! Put me down . - ( Jake laughing ) I missed you , man !
( Ellen ) And then he wrote dirty words all over the garage .
He was ... your daddy was five . He was your age .
- I 'm almost six . - So is Jake .
( Laughter )
Oh , look at that face . OK , do the other one .
( Beeping )
Now that 's closer to the real truth .
Oh , you . This guy was always getting into some sort of mischief .
I got no doubt about that .
Was Uncle Sean ever bad ? Did you ever spank him ?
Sharp shirt , Jake .
Hey , may your sex life be as busy as your shirt .
Why , thank you .
My tea set ! I got my tea set !
Oh , let me see !
( Jake 's wife ) Every lovely lady should have a tea set .
( Thea ) It has a teapot and cups and saucers .
( Jake 's wife ) And a sugar bowl and a creamer .
( Thea ) Can I put real tea in it ? ( Jake 's wife ) Yes , real tea .
( Thea ) Can I make sandwiches ? ( Carla ) Yes .
( Woman ) Thea , we forgot the Christmas carols .
( Jake ) Carol from the grocery store ? ( Jake 's wife ) Oh , will you stop it ?
# Hark , the herald angels sing
# Glory to the newborn King ... #
I miss him , Mom .
( Singing continues )
- I want you to change your work . - Mom , please don 't start that .
- You could teach or write ... - I 'm not gonna quit now .
( Laughter inside )
You 're all I have left . I don 't want you working in the water .
# Glory to the newborn King ... #
Mom , what I do is perfectly safe .
At the moment , we 're collecting big snails .
Jake and I are scientists . We 're almost PhDs .
We know what we 're doing . There 's nothing to worry about .
# Christ is born in Bethlehem ... #
( Ellen ) Oh , great .
( Chattering on boat )
And , well , we have to dig the ditch really deep ...
so the water 'll go all the way around and we can swim in it .
( Giggles ) You 're silly .
You know what ? Let 's pretend this is Buckingham Palace .
And you 'll be Princess Di , and we 'll have a parade with horses .
And you 'll ride in a golden carriage , and we 'll ...
( Thea ) And I can invite Cinderella to the ball .
She 'll come in a golden carriage , too .
( Thea , distant ) And we can have cookies and punch and cake .
And I can invite Prince Charlie and ...
What 's the name of the other prince ?
Grandma ? Grandma ?
What 's wrong ?
Nothing .
Oh , we better get this done before the tide comes in .
It 's not nice to be evasive .
My mother says that to my father all the time .
( Ellen chuckles )
( Hoagie ) Hello , you two !
Hello .
I don 't know why I fish here .
I never catch anything .
There must be a sign underwater - 'beware , Hoagie 's about ' .
- You drive the plane . - Flies the plane .
Mostly , it 's like driving .
What 's that , an excavation ?
We 're building a sand castle , and you 're invited for tea .
( Jake ) You know why you got no ambition ?
- ( Michael ) Why is that , Jake ? - Your Norman Rockwell life .
Norman Rockwell ?
That 's precisely your problem , my friend .
You weren 't exactly a deprived kid .
I don 't buy that roots-rock-reggae bullshit .
Cut that hair , you 're a three-piece suit .
The bottom line is we got three months left of work and no money .
Spent it all on beer .
Bahamian Fisheries Department is not exactly Fort Knox , my friend .
But , on the other hand ,
Office of Naval Research , they 've got money .
No . Forget it .
What do you mean ? Money is money .
- They put bombs on dolphins . - What you talking about ?
I know a guy who got money from them to study eels .
( Man ) It 's hard to put a bomb on an eel !
Who rattled your cage ? Michael , man !
We 're bustin ' our bunghies to get our degrees .
I 'm tired of all this paradise shit .
It 's getting on my last nerve , man .
( Jake ) William . Look at you , boy .
- What ? - A mental midget reading all day .
If mediocrity were fattening , you 'd all be whales .
Knock off that drumming ' !
( Jake ) Look at you , boy . What 's wrong with you ?
You think because you been to university you 're smart ?
( Ellen ) I don 't know why I 've told you all this .
Sometimes talking to a stranger is easier .
I can 't explain it . It 's just something I feel .
I always listen to my feelings .
I think I 'm going crazy . Nightmares and ...
Maybe it was an accident .
It was no accident .
I 'm not saying you 're wrong .
I 'm just saying that maybe there are other possibilities .
When it killed Sean , I knew with certainty it had come for him .
I knew that !
I know it 's coming .
What 's it cost to ride on that plane ?
The water 's coming in ! The water 's coming in !
Depends on where you want to go .
- Doesn 't matter . - ( Thea ) Hurry !
- Just like that ? - Just like that .
Oh ! Oh , no ! Oh ! Oh !
( Hoagie ) Take the wheel ! ( Ellen ) I 'm sorry ?
- Take the wheel . - No , I can 't .
- Sure , you can . - I don 't know how .
Nobody does till they learn .
What are you doing ?
Better take the wheel or we 'll be swimming soon .
( Hoagie ) Whoa , take it easy ! Take it easy !
Hold her gently . She 'll damn near fly herself .
See ? Just like driving a car .
Where do I pull off the road ?
No , you 're doing fine . I 'll keep you out of trouble .
- Relax . - Where are we going ?
One time , I was flying supplies up the Amazon
when I came down in the jungle .
- You won 't tell me ? - I was picked up by head-hunters ,
and taken to their chief .
- You are impossible ! - He looked at me
and took me in his hut .
Inside his hut , there was a long pole ...
( Carnival music )
( Ellen ) What is all this ?
Just a little something I arranged to cheer you up .
- No , really . - What ?
- Tell me , what is all this ? - A local festival .
It 's called a junkanoo .
( Michael ) ' I 'm not hearing anything up here , buddy . '
How many have you tagged , exactly ? How many ?
Michael ... stop busting my bunghie .
Yeah , it 's OK for you , but not for me , huh ?
Have no fear , Jake is here .
I just struck the mother lode . I 'm counting .
( Michael ) ' Watch yourself with that fancy equipment , buddy . '
Such a live wire 'll make your hair stick up funny .
That 's good , Michael . William ?
Yeah , there 's no hope for that boy .
Jake ? Jake , that 's a joke .
Holy shit !
We got a big fish down here , man .
Oh , yeah ? How big ?
- Jesus ! - Look out !
( Hoagie ) What 's wrong ?
Ellen ?
Jesus Christ !
- ( Hoagie ) Ellen , what 's wrong ? - Nothing . Nothing . I 'm fine .
- No , you 're not . - I 'm terrific .
Come on !
Give it up !
You can 't keep doing this .
- I can 't keep doing THIS . - You promised me a drink .
Sharks come and go , Ellen . People have nothing to do with it .
- A drink with an umbrella in it . - Ellen , give it up .
Give it a kick in the arse .
Get on with your life .
I know what you 've been through .
Don 't worry . The nightmares 'll go away .
Give me my glasses , man .
( Crew man ) Boy , I ain 't never seen nothin ' so big . Never !
I was right next to Michael . The thing went right past me !
Should 've gone for you , Jake . Why did it come up ?
- What 's it doing in warm water ? - What 's the difference ?
It 's only a shark . A big , big , beautiful shark .
And it 's ours . Don 't say anything to anyone .
Fishermen would try to kill it . Michael , we got us a great white .
Now we gonna do some real research .
Do me a favour , don 't say anything about this to my mom .
Hey , man , I didn 't mean to , you know , flap my lips , eh ?
( Ellen laughing )
( Indistinct chattering )
( Hoagie ) So ... ( Ellen ) So ?
I said to him , 'Where 's the disinfectant ? '
He said , ' I 've left it in town . '
So I said , 'What are we gonna do ? '
So he says , 'I 'll tell you what we 'll do .
'Come back at lunchtime , all the flies will be in the kitchen . '
( Both laugh )
( Carla ) Come to bed .
He took her sightseeing .
Well , you work . I work .
She needs someone to help her take her mind off things .
( Laughing continues )
I 'll help you take YOUR mind off things , sailor .
It 's soaking .
( Sighs ) Thank you .
Good night .
( Thunderclap )
( Crowds chattering )
( Mouthing )
Louisa .
It 's OK , Jake . I 'll check on the table .
( Cheering )
- ( Hoagie ) OK , everything rides . - Ooh , it 's Hoagie !
Hey , come on , I wanna see this .
Oh , that 's Hoagie , all right .
( Excited chatter )
( Hoagie ) Everything on the line .
- You 're not betting it all ? - All or nothing at all .
- Here , do you want to throw for me ? - No !
Now get ready . Are you ready ?
( Shouting , cheering )
( Crowd groans )
- I guess that 's bad ? - Depends on your point of view .
( Jake ) Ooh , look at that . Come here .
Ooh , look at you . You look great !
( Chattering )
It 's on the house .
I knew there was a reason I could afford this .
Thank you , Shirley !
My father used to say , ' Jake , you got two loves in your life -
'what you do and who you 're with . '
- Happy birthday , Louisa . - Happy birthday !
- And a Happy New Year . - ( All ) Happy New Year !
- Happy New Year . - Happy New Year .
Don 't go weak in the knees on me tonight , boy .
You 're gonna need all the strength you got .
I knew a one-armed piano player ,
took two minutes to play the Minute Waltz .
Watch how you talk . Michael and I are about to be famous .
- Tell ' em . - Jake !
No job talk . You promised .
You promised .
Right .
Would you risk a dance with me , madam ?
- You 'll be sorry . - So will you . I have two right feet .
That 's good , I have two left .
Well , that 's a set .
( Slow dance music )
# I , I was a game he would play ... #
A little quiet tonight .
- New Year 's blues ? - No , not at all .
Come on . It 's my party .
He 's just Michael , he 's startin ' to count them damn conch in his sleep .
( Louisa laughs )
Excuse me .
- Mind if I cut in ? - Please .
The world would be a better place
if more sons danced with their mothers .
Michael , stop pouting .
You look like you did when you were six and didn 't get what you wanted .
I like him . I enjoy his company .
( Michael ) Yeah . I don 't like him chasing around after you .
I don 't trust him .
( Ellen ) He 's not chasing . You are being ridiculous .
I 've been a pain in the ass and I 'm sorry .
I 'm not gonna bother you about your work .
- You 're not a pain . - Let me finish .
I 've been rehearsing this all day .
Sean 's death almost killed me . I 'll never get over it ,
but I refuse to let myself be run by an obsession .
I can 't keep on believing it was intentional .
I finally figured it out .
Good .
That 's it , ' good ' ?
I thought you 'd break out the champagne .
No , I-I-I 'm pleased .
Come on . Show your mother what a good dancer you are .
# Oh , you can surely see
# You 're someone more to me #
Where is everybody ?
( Jake ) Down here !
( Humming )
- Where is Clarence and William ? - I gave them the day off .
What for ? We got a job to finish .
Why are you making a transmitter ?
It 's all part of the master plan .
We 're gonna test it out right now .
We 're gonna learn about its motor systems , its heart rate .
( Heartbeat )
We 're going to study a magnificent animal
no one knows that much about .
As the sun sets , we bid a fond farewell to the family of conch .
What the hell are you talking about ?
We wrap it up and hand it in . Why is your heart stronger than mine ?
We don 't write up anything till we 're finished .
When I was a boy , my father said ,
'Never do anything today you can put off till tomorrow . '
Them conch gonna be there tomorrow .
- When we got the grant , it said ... - No , when I got the grant .
- OK , when I signed on , I ... - When I invited you .
- We got the grant together . - When we got it together .
We got three months ' work left on this . We can 't write a report .
Michael , we got a rare bird here . You know that , huh ?
Great white don 't come down to the Bahamas , never .
Do we let an opportunity just swim away ?
My name 's on the report .
A half-assed job , I don 't get my doctorate and neither do you .
I thought we were planning a rosy future together .
So did I.
Hey ! Hey !
( Knocking ) Michael ?
Anybody home in there at all ?
You better beam down to Earth with the rest of us .
If that shark 's still in the water , it won 't be there forever .
It 's gonna figure out the water 's too warm .
Look at me and tell me you don 't want to study that fish as much as I do .
Michael ? Huh ? This is what we trained for .
This is what we studied them damn books for .
Remember , my name goes on that report , too .
It 's as important to me as it is to you , right ?
All right , you like them damn snails ?
All right , all right , I 'll make you a deal . Listen .
We study that shark , just for a few days ,
and it 's back to your lovely snails .
Now that 's fair , man . That 's fair .
Come on , indulge me with it , eh ?
I don 't know shit about electronics .
Boy , you don 't know shit about anything .
( Laughing ) It 's time you learned .
I 'll teach you how to wear your hair , how to dance .
How to box . Come on , follow me .
Get your butt down here , man .
This is the third time you 've forgotten to take it out .
- I got a lot on my mind . - You can 't remember when they come ?
My brain is shrinking ...
Don 't give me that preoccupied scientist crap .
( Carla ) I 'm getting ready for a big event !
( Michael ) I thought artists worked with their subconscious .
How come it 's my responsibility ?
( Carla ) Because .
Oh . OK , now I understand . All you had to do was explain it .
I take out the garbage ... because .
I 'm glad we got that straightened out .
We don 't have anything straightened out .
You 're uptight about something .
What 's wrong ?
Why should there be anything wrong ? I 'm enjoying my day off ,
my wife starts yelling at me about the garbage .
What are we arguing about ?
I don 't know . I ... ( Chuckles )
I don 't know .
Hey .
- No fair , I 'm not armed . - Then don 't come any closer .
- Turn it off . Off . - No . I have work .
I 've always wanted to make love to an angry welder .
I 've dreamed of nothing else since I was a small boy .
- Shut the door . - Uh-huh . Later .
( Giggling )
- Mmm ! Mmm ! - Michael !
Shut the door !
( Giggling )
( Michael ) You sure you 've done this before ?
Oh , yeah . Lots of times . Trust your Uncle Jake , eh ?
It 's always worked , huh ?
Well , uh ... thus far .
OK , take me out .
Little more .
There it is ! Comin ' ! It 's comin ' !
- You remember how to pull rope , eh ? - Yeah .
( Screaming )
Yes ! You got him , man !
Ah ! Now would be a good time !
Did you see that , man ?
( Michael ) Let 's try to follow it .
Now we 're gonna see if Uncle Jake 's equipment 's really working for us .
( Jake ) Michael !
- Our little island agrees with you . - I have my own little island .
But it 's so cold in the winter . I tried winter once .
Here we are . Burlington , Vermont .
I flew a run to New York . Oh !
I have a bone in my left foot that hasn 't thawed yet .
- When I was a small boy ... - Not hard to imagine , by the way .
.. I dreamed of always being warm .
What do you want ? Whatever we had last time .
Two Bahama Mamas , please .
- Stay . I 'll take time off . - You always take time off .
I like to travel . I 'll nick the plane again .
- Won 't you get in trouble ? - Not if he doesn 't find out .
It 's just a hop down to the Caribbean . We 'll spend a few days .
There must be a lot of ladies who 'd be glad to go .
Yeah , there are , but ...
I 've grown tired of one-way conversations .
I have an irresistible urge to kiss you , Ellen Brody .
Why ?
Because it would not occur to you why .
Blushing suits you .
- Lord ... I 'm sorry . - It 's nothing to be sorry about .
No , this whole thing ... The whole idea is preposterous .
I don 't think so .
- You sure you don 't need glasses ? - I 'm a pilot .
My vision is perfect .
( Jake ) What are we getting ? ( Michael ) Nine knots .
Shit ! We should be keeping up .
- You sure the throttle 's open ? - Wide open .
Come on , you overgrown goldfish ! Come to Uncle Jake .
- How long have you known Hoagie ? - What ?
How long have you known Hoagie ?
- What 's he got to do with it ? - How long ?
Since he got here . Bring it to starboard !
When did he get here ?
- Who ? - Hoagie !
Christ ! One day he was just here , that 's all .
( Michael ) What do you know about him ?
He 's after my mother .
- What 's so funny ? - He 's not good enough for her , eh ?
I agree . I 'd send her home right now .
Bring her about , we 're going the wrong way .
I mean , some of these pilots are flying drugs down here .
- He 's always going off somewhere . - Bring her about , now !
- I am ! - Hurry , man , we 're losin ' him !
- You must know something . - Christ !
He likes gambling , he likes women , don 't bother me !
- He flies charter ... - Damn ! We lost him !
Maybe your gear crapped out .
Maybe you crapped out , flapping ' your lips about Hoagie .
Maybe he 's gone .
All right , Mr Fish .
We 'll come back and find you tomorrow .
All he did was kiss me !
- ( Carla ) Well , that 's a beginning . - A beginning of what ?
To whatever happens next .
Oh .
I used to think I could handle these situations once I was grown up ,
but I don 't even know if he 's serious .
Mmm , give it some time , Ellen . See what happens .
Well , part of me wanted to go off with him .
I couldn 't .
I don 't know why he wants me .
Maybe he 's got good taste .
He hasn 't spent much time with a woman like you .
I don 't know what he thinks . Or what I think . This is so silly !
I feel too old to be in this thing .
I hope not . I am counting on a long , happy sex life .
( Both chuckle )
( Creaking )
You said it wasn 't polite to interrupt people .
Yes , I did .
- It 's time for tea , Grandma . - Oh , I almost forgot .
I didn 't . I put everything in my room .
My teddy bear 's joining us .
( Ellen laughs )
( Gasps )
Michael ?
Michael , what is it ?
Nothing , just a stupid dream .
Hmm .
( Sighs )
Time for bed , peanut .
- Oh , no ! - Yep . Daddy 's got homework .
- But you let me last night . - Yeah , yeah .
Mommy 's waiting to read a story .
- Good night , sweetheart ! - Good night .
Night . Let 's put up our feet and shoot the breeze ,
or whatever it is beer drinkers do .
I , uh , I got to put together this report , Ma .
Jake says don 't do today what you can put off tomorrow .
Yeah , Jake 's got a lot of those .
I 'm leaving in a few days . I don 't want to go with you unhappy .
I 'm not unhappy .
I saw you and Thea . You looked just like your father .
Do you remember when you guys used to imitate him ?
Mom , I gotta get this finished , OK ?
- I worry about you . - There 's nothing to worry about .
I 'm your mother . It 's my job .
Just cos you 're a man doesn 't mean I 've retired .
I 've worked on MY smile . It 's ... it 's your turn .
That 's better .
( Jake on radio ) 'Blump , blump ! Blump , blump !
- ' Blump , blump ! Blump , blump ! ' - Jake , knock it off !
Blump , blump . OK , just don 't try to renege on our deal .
Half a day on the snails , then a half a day on the shark .
You got 17 more minutes , then we 're gonna go look for that shark .
( Michael ) It 's a big ocean . We could spend the rest of our lives looking .
'We 're gonna find him . '
'I got about a half a dozen . I 'll tag ' em and be right up .
'You , uh , hearing ' anything ? '
Nothin ' at all . Just another cool , calm , tickly day in the Bahamas .
Just stay within a quarter mile . I got a three-mile monitor radius .
Within three miles , there 's plenty of time to beam your ugly ass up .
( Electronic heartbeat )
Michael , I got him .
'He 's comin ' towards you . You better get out now . '
All right , I 'm comin ' , I 'm comin ' .
( Monitor beat quickens )
Shit !
Jake !
Michael ! Michael !
'Michael ! '
Michael , what 's goin ' on ? Michael , can you hear me ?
'Michael ! Michael , can you hear me ? '
( Grunting )
( Breathing fast )
Michael !
( Panting )
( Latch creaking )
( Grunting )
Son of a bitch ! Oh , shit !
Jesus Christ !
( Metal clanging )
Ah !
( Gurgling and gasping )
Uh !
( Jake ) It 's over there !
Shit ! Get the bang sticks , we 're goin ' down .
- They 're no good . - Get another one !
( Grunting and panting )
( Jake ) Come on , come on ! Michael !
- Get him up ! Watch his arm ! - ( Clarence ) Lay him down gently !
( Jake ) We need a tourniquet to stop his bleeding .
- ( William ) Try this ! - Get the wet suit off .
( Jake ) Keep cool , don 't worry .
( William ) Michael , how are you ? I think he may be in shock .
( Jake ) Clarence , move it !
Hey , hey , hey ! Hey , what you doin ' , man ?
No one goes in the water till we know where that fish is .
You fall off the horse , you get right back on .
Hell , what kind of bullcrap you talkin ' ? Huh ?
- Anybody 's in the water , it 's me . - Jake , I 'm gonna go down .
All right , so what about Carla 's gig ? It 's almost time , man .
Michael , I can 't just let you go back down .
I 'm scared shitless .
What the hell do I do if I can 't go back in that water ?
All right , be careful .
Clarence , get up on that shack . Give us some lookout .
- I hope he knows what he 's doing . - He 's doin ' what he 's got to do .
Jake , are you gettin anything on the shark ?
No , everything 's cool .
I 'm thinkin ' about yesterday . It 's probably a mistake .
- He was hungry . You look tasty . - But how come only me ?
- Maybe he just like white meat . - You 're a funny guy , Jake .
Jesus !
( Laughter and applause )
( Man ) It is about art that I wish to speak today .
The raw material of art surrounds us all ,
catching in the net that each and every one of us casts
into the current of life .
- But it takes the art ... - Where the hell are they ?
They 'll be here .
- Can I go on the banana boat ? - Shh !
Margaret 's going . She 's with her mother .
- OK . - Oh , boy ! Oh , boy !
- Thea , you be careful . - I will , I will !
- ( Ellen ) Thea ! - It 's OK . Banana boats are fun .
Oh , we should be so lucky . I wish we were out with her playing ' .
Margaret , wait for me !
'Get to the point , man , ' as my wife now says .
( Laughter and applause )
OK . Well , in short , art is grease for the wheel of life .
Today we are privileged to dedicate a work of art .
Carla Brody ,
an artist of growing reputation ,
was commissioned to express our way of life in permanent form ...
to show the world what we all know right here on this beach :
that it is better in the Bahamas .
- ( Woman ) Absolutely . - Ladies and gentlemen , Carla Brody !
Thank you , Commissioner Witherspoon , Mrs Witherspoon .
Thea !
Oh , my God !
Stop ! Come back ! Bring her back !
( Screaming )
Stop ! Thea ! Thea !
Thea !
Somebody do something !
Oh , no ! My God !
- Mommy ! Mommy ! - Thea !
( Man ) Somebody get a doctor ! Get a doctor now !
( Man ) Quickly !
( Engine revs )
- I 'm sorry I missed you . - Where have you been ?
What 's the matter ? What happened ?
Thea was attacked by a shark .
Oh , my God .
The doctor said she should be OK . She 's in shock .
Sweetheart ? Sweetheart ?
I 'm so sorry . I should 've known . Jesus .
Should 've known what ?
- We tried to keep track of him . - Of ...
The shark .
- You knew ? - Yeah . Thought it went away .
- Came after me . - She could 've been killed . You knew ?
And you didn 't tell us ? You let your mother think ...
Where is she ?
- How could you do that ? - Where 's my mother ?
- Where 's my mother ? - Why didn 't you tell us ?
- Where 's Jake ? - WHY DIDN 'T YOU TELL US ?
( Carla ) Michael !
Jake !
- Jake ! - What ?
Come on ! I need you ! Hurry up !
Hoagie ! Did you see our boat ?
- ( Hoagie ) I just got here . - My mother took it .
- I hope she 's a good sailor . - A shark attacked Thea .
She went after the damn thing .
- She 's gone after it ? - Yeah , we gotta stop her .
In that ? It 'll take all day in that bathtub .
Got a better idea ?
I 'll radio her position .
The rescue boats will pick her up , so don 't worry .
She 'll be fine .
She 'll never find that bloody shark . We couldn 't .
( Michael ) It 'll find her . ( Jake ) What do you mean ?
She said it was coming .
- What do you mean ? - What do you know ?
She thinks the shark that killed Martin and Sean
is following the family .
Hey , he 's not talkin about our shark , eh ?
What do you do when you 're not flying people ?
I deliver laundry .
( Hoagie ) Hold on . What 's that ? Let 's have a look .
Oh .
( Hoagie ) It 's a big ocean out there .
( Michael ) Can 't this thing go any faster ?
Any faster , this thing 'll be a flying Cuisinart
and we 'll be diced into oblivion .
Come and get me , you son of a bitch .
There she is . That 's her right there .
Is that what I think it is ?
- Mom ... - Hold on !
Oh !
( Hoagie ) ' Thomas , you there ? This is Zero-Papa-Alpha here . '
( Man on radio ) 'Hoagie , where are you ? '
12 miles southeast of Emerald Key . Look for Neptune 's Folly . '
I need two boats fast and somebody who can kill a shark - a big one .
( Man ) ' What 're you doing ? ' ( Hoagie ) Practising landing .
Hang on to your socks , lads .
Wait ! You sure you know how to do this ?
Of course not ! What kind of pilot do you think I am ?
- Christ ! - Hell , not half bad .
Get out , I 'll keep it busy .
No , it 'll come for the plane 's electromagnetic impulse .
( Hoagie ) Get the bloody hell out !
Michael !
Damn passengers ! You 're all the same . Complain , complain ...
Oh , shit !
Hoagie !
Hoagie ! Hoagie !
Why 'd you come out here ?
- Why did you bring him ? - Mom , Mom !
- Why 'd you take the boat ? - It kept coming !
- Didn 't you realise ? - There was nothing else to do .
- You shouldn 't have done it . - I tried to tell you .
I tried . ( Sobbing )
( Hoagie ) Hey ! Give me a hand , for Christ 's sake !
- Hoagie ! - How the hell did you do that , man ?
- It wasn 't easy , believe me . - Get him up .
( Grunting )
( Jake ) You all right , man ?
- Oh ! Bloody hell . - ( Jake ) Get it started !
- The breath on that thing ! - You are alive !
Let 's get out of here , Ellen Brody . Oh !
Good , this thing 's still working .
( Engine spluttering )
That 's your engine , pal . I 'll have a look .
( Electronic beating )
Oh , shit , he 's close , man .
- What is that sound ? - The shark 's heartbeat .
Hoagie , try to finish . Michael , gimme a hand , I got an idea .
We 're taking water down here . Ellen , start pumping here .
( Hoagie ) Ellen ! Get the bilge pump !
( Jake ) Take the radio transmitter out and hook it to the strobe .
- We gotta get the engine started ! - Just do it !
We 're gonna feed that big boy a meal he won 't forget .
You better have something good going . We 've got a rotten hose .
There 's a spare one . What you wanna do with this ?
I 'm rigging ' the receiver . We get it inside that bastard and set it off .
I got it . We rig an antenna on this , we can shock the hell out of him .
Right ! You 're learning .
( Beating intensifies )
He 's getting closer !
They spend their lives looking for food , they don 't care what it is .
Maybe he 's got indigestion . He 's eaten my plane !
It 's not food he 's after .
Michael , turn on your switch . I need a test .
- Anybody tell you you 're nuts ? - All the time .
If it responds to external electrical impulse ,
it might respond to one inside - confuse him , drive him crazy .
- ( Electrical whine ) - OK , a test ... Good .
You 'd better get up here ! The heartbeat 's stopped !
Shit .
Either he 's gone or your gear 's crapped out again .
That 's bull . My equipment don 't crap out . He 'll be back .
( Jake ) Get me the boat hook .
( Hoagie ) Maybe he had a heart attack . Humans are full of cholesterol .
- Give me that . - Shit ! Where is he ?
Give me that line , Michael . Right there .
There he is !
( Hoagie ) Ellen , try the engine .
Ellen ! Try to start the engine !
( Engine starts )
Son of a bitch . Let 's get out of here .
No , it 's too late , Hoagie . Give me a hard port .
Right !
( Michael ) Here , give me that . ( Jake ) No ! No time for that !
Jake ! You can 't go out there without a line !
Keep it steady . It 's gonna come back !
Damn thing 's disappeared . He 's gone !
( Electronic heartbeat )
Jake !
We 're taking too much water . It 'll stop the engine .
Ellen , take the wheel . We 've got to outrun it . Ellen !
- That thing gonna work ? - It 'll work .
If Jake says so , it will . This charge will drive it crazy .
( High-pitched drone )
( Roaring )
( Drone turns to patchy static )
Sweet Jesus , we 're headed straight for it !
Ellen , come about !
( Drone resumes )
( Roaring )
( Hoagie ) We 're gonna hit it ! Hold on !
Hold on !
Smile , you son of a bitch !
- Michael ! - Come over here .
Michael !
It 's all right ! I 'm OK !
( Man ) Anybody there ? Over here !
Jake !
Michael , you got a minute ?
It 's Jake !
Son of a bitch !
Jesus , Jake .
What took you so damn long , man ?
What the hell are you doing alive ?
I told you Uncle Jake 's equipment don 't crap out , eh ?
You 're not going to do something stupid like die on me , are you ?
No , man . I 'm way too mean for that .
So from now on , we 're going to study snails , eh ?
Yeah .
( Ellen ) Come to Amity this summer .
( Carla ) We 'll be there . ( Ellen ) You make sure they come .
( Thea ) I will . I 'll miss you , Grandma .
Get in , Ellen Brody . You 'll miss your plane .
- Goodbye , Grandma ! - OK .
- Be careful . - OK . See ya .
- Take good care of Jake . - I will .
You gonna be OK ?
- Yeah . - OK .
When I come back , remind me to tell you about the time
I took a hundred nuns to Nairobi .
( Hoagie ) There they were , 100 nuns , playing guitars
and singing , ' The hills are alive with the sound of music . '
Then suddenly , one comes up to me and she says ,
'There 's smoke coming from the engine . '
But I never took them seriously ,
until they all started singing 'Nearer My God to Thee . '
Ripped by thewildbunch22